你知道海狮和海豹有什么区别吗
What's the difference between a sea lion and a seal?
怎么了  宝贝儿
What's that, baby?
海狮和海豹有什么区别
What's the difference between a sea lion and a seal?
海豹说的是实话而海狮总是撒谎吗
Um, seals tell the truth, but a sea lion's always lyin'?
海豹一词也有保证的意思
狮子和撒谎两词是谐音
是海狮有耳朵啦
A sea lion has ears.
对  可不是吗
Yeah, that's right.
我忘了
I forgot.
等我们到了动物园我指给你看
I'll show you when we get to the zoo.
我们今晚能吃披萨吗
Can we have pizza tonight?
我来不成了  戴茜  我
I'm not gonna be here, Daisy. I'm--
我得赶回去  还记得吗
I'm going back on the road, remember?
你才在这儿呆了两天
You've only been here for two days.
这次我三个星期后就回来
I'll be back in three weeks this time.
谁来救救她
Somebody help her!
她癫痫发作了
She's having a seizure!
在铁轨上发作
On the track?
看啊  有位女士躺在铁轨上
Yeah, there's a lady down there.
爸爸  回来
Daddy, come back!
爸爸
Daddy!
女士  你没事吧
Hey. Lady, are you okay?
快  快点儿  快醒醒
Come on, come on, hey, wake up!
快  起来  喂
Come on! Get up! Hey!
快点儿
Come on.
帮帮我
Help me!
谁来帮帮我
Somebody help me!
上来  快点
Come on! Hurry up!
快点
Hurry up!
爸爸
Daddy!
快开车  快开车
Move the train! Move the train!
伙计  你还好吗
Hey, man, are you okay?
我想是的
Yeah, I think so.
她患有癫痫
She's epileptic.
快  我们把你拉上来
Come on, let's get you up.
你抓紧她了吗
You got her?
是  抓紧了
Yeah, we got her.
宝贝儿  我没事
Hey, sweetie, I'm okay.
爸爸
Daddy?
我在急诊室发现了这个病例
I found this case, uh, in the E.R.--
白人  男性  三十五六
white male, mid 30s,
意识丧失
loss of consciousness,
心电图异常
abnormal EKG.
还有  他是那位地铁英雄
And he's the subway hero.
你的热情真是让人难以忘怀
Your enthusiasm is impressive.
可惜陈述报告做得太乏味了
Wish I could say the same about your presentation.
是个医生都知道该先陈述
Everybody knows you lead with
最有意思的症状
your most interesting symptom.
你说得没错
You're right.
心电图比意识丧失更有意思  所以
EKG is more interesting than loss of consciousness, so--
天呐  她还在说  让她消停会儿吧
God, she's still talking. Make it stop.
豪斯的世界观里
House's worldview
可没有见义勇为或者无私奉献这类事情
doesn't include random acts of self-sacrifice.
在被切实否定之前
He's gonna count heroism as a symptom
他会把英雄主义当做症状之一
until proven otherwise.
这家伙干了件了不起的事
The guy did a wonderful thing.
我们难道不能相信其表吗
Can't we just take that at face value?
你真是可爱
You are adorable.
英雄主义确实存在的
Heroism does exist.
那个把飞机迫降到哈迪逊河上的人算吗
What about the guy who landed the plane in the Hudson?
简讯  那家伙本来就在飞机上
News flash--that guy was already on the plane.
就我们所知  在面临必死无疑之时
For all we know, he would have killed everyone else on board
如果杀掉机上其他人能提高存活几率的话
if it increased his chances.
他早就大开杀戒了
Faced with almost certain death,
正常人都会冷眼旁观
a normal person rides the pine.
那消防员怎么解释
What about firefighters?
那些要接受过几个月的训练
The guys who undergo months of training
来抗拒自我保护的本能的家伙们呢
to deny their own instincts for self-preservation?
而这名病人并不是消防员
And the patient isn't a firefighter.
他是一支乐队的贝斯手
He plays a bass in a band.
这么说人性本无情  自私又自利
So humanity is apathetic and self-serving?
当然
Yeah.
我也曾被抢劫过
I was mugged once.
当我看到枪时  我腿就软了
When I saw the gun, my legs went out.
我总以为这是战或逃的抉择
I always thought it was fight or flight.
不知道可以是战或逃  还可以倒
Didn't know it was fight or flight or faint.
随你们怎么嘲笑好了
Laugh all you want.
剩下那百来号人不也站在站台上吗
The other hundred people stayed on that platform.
这是面对危险的自然反应
That's a normal response to danger.
胆小鬼发话了
The coward has spoken.
我们病人的问题是神经上的
Our patient's problem is neurological.
交感神经的兴奋  刺激了大脑
Sympathetic stimulation-- stress to the brain
导致了心脏的反应
triggers a response in the heart.
去  检查下这位超人的大脑边缘系统是否有肿块
Go forth and look for masses in Clark Kent's limbic system.
看来你挺受瞩目的啊
Seems like you're getting a bit of attention.
每个人都特地过来
Everyone keeps going out of their way
问我有什么需要的
asking me if I need anything.
感觉挺不错
It's kind of nice.
当时都发生了什么
So what happened out there?
我不太记得了
I don't really remember.
只有一些影像  像闪回一样
It's just images, like flashes.
我的意识似乎处于自动驾驶模式
I kind of went on autopilot.
直到上了救护车
My memory doesn't go back into real time
我的记忆才回到现实
until I was in the ambulance.
我在书上读到过
I read that's pretty common
这对死里逃生的人来说很常见
for people in life-or-death situations.
杰克
Jack.
亲爱的  这位是我妻子  伊娃
Honey. Uh, this is my wife, Eva.
你还好吗
Are you okay?
我很好
Yeah, I'm fine.
他们只是在给我做些检查
They're just doing some tests.
戴茜怎么样了
How's Daisy?
老实说  她不太好
She's not so good, actually.
她亲眼看着自己的父亲
She watched her father
在飞驰而来的列车前纵身跳下
jump in front of a train.
她还在发抖  一直哭个不停
She's still shaking. She can't stop crying.
你为什么要这么对她
Why would you do that to her?
他救了那个女人的命
He saved a woman's life.
他本可能因此送命
He could have died.
你想过自己的家人吗
Did you even think about your family?
我需要你的建议
I need your advice.
周四和你妈妈一起吃晚饭的事
Dinner with your mom on Thursday.
那可是我的生日
It's my birthday.
我知道
I know.
我肯定会来的
I'm definitely coming,
但威尔森买了香港电影节的票
but Wilson's got tickets to the Hong Kong film festival.
自从他单身以后  他一直一蹶不振
Ever since his breakup, he's been a mess.
我还没跟他说我去不成了
I haven't been able to tell him that I'm not going,
所以如果你碰巧见到他
so maybe if you happen to see him,
能否告诉他这有多重要
you could mention how important this is.
你应该去陪威尔森
You should go.
什么  那怎么行
What? I can't.
这可是你的生日啊
It's your birthday.
这  这  这没事
Oh, it's--it's-- it's fine.
你关心你的朋友  那很好
It's sweet that you care about your friend,
而且老实说  反正你迟早也会发现
and, frankly, as you will find out sooner or later,
我妈妈是个难对付的主
my mother is a handful.
去吧
Go.
我需要你的建议
I need your advice.
关于这次电影节的事儿
This film festival.
我两个月前就买好票了
I have had these tickets for two months.
是  我知道
Yeah, I know.
我肯定会去的
I'm definitely coming.
那就好
Okay.
但周四是卡迪的生日
But Thursday is Cuddy's birthday,
而且她妈妈也会来  共进晚餐什么的
and her mom's coming down-- it's a whole dinner thing.
我在想  如果你见到她
And I thought, maybe if you see her,
能否告诉她你有多不开心
you could mention how upset you've been.
这你得去
You have to go.
你女朋友的生日
Your girlfriend's birthday?
毫无疑问的事情
It's not even a question.
她每年都能过生日
She has one every year.
你多久能和挚爱分一次手啊
How often do you break up with the love of your life?
好吧  就你来说  还真不算少  但
Okay, for you, it's more often than most, but still...
我是成年人了  死不了的
I'm a big boy. I think I'll survive.
我一定会想办法补偿你的
I will definitely make this up to you.
我今晚回家路上
Am I imagining things,
竟然看见你的脸上了广告板
or did I see a billboard with your face on it
是不是幻视了
on my way home tonight?
是整张脸吗  我只看到一个鼻子
Oh, was my whole face there? 'Cause I just saw the nose.
我记得你说是
I thought you said they were taking
是和好多医生一起拍的照片
a picture of a bunch of doctors together.
拍的时候确实是
They did.
完全不知道怎么会只有我一个人上了广告
I have no idea how it ended up just me.
因为你模样挺正的
Well, you are pretty cute.
你是在跟我调情吗
You're flirting with me?
这屋里没别人了呀
I don't see anyone else in the room.
怎么了
What?
我也说不好
I don't know.
自从你交了网上男友之后
Things have been a little tense around here
家里气氛一直有点儿紧张
since that whole online-boyfriend thing.
菲尔不是我男朋友
Phil's not my boyfriend.
有问题的人不是我
I'm not the one with the problem.
怎么不是  是你心里有别人
No, you're the one with feelings for someone else.
你还是我丈夫
You're still my husband.
我仍然爱你
I still love you.
我想跟你和谐相处
And I want things to be okay between us.
而且呢  你现在成了名模
Also, you're a famous model now.
更酷了
That's pretty cool...
有点小性感
Sexy, even.
我要越过颈动脉分叉...
So I advance through the carotid bifurcation...
你这是提问吗
Are you asking?
对  是提问
Yes, I'm asking.
我只在书上学过操作步骤
I've only read how to do it.
但理论和实际是两回事
Practice is different than theory.
告诉我该怎么做就好
Just tell me how to do it.
在眼动脉分支处
You're going to inject dye
注射造影剂
just past the takeoff for the optic artery.
好  现在吗
Right. Now?
血压在上升
His B.P.'s going up.
身体对操作有不良反应
The procedure's stressing his body.
那我该怎么办
Well, what do I do?
暂停操作
Hold on a minute.
给他点时间平复
Just give him a chance to regain equilibrium.
血压升高  心率180
B.P.'s up, heart rate's 180.
我该怎么办
W-what should I do?
导管给我  去推急救车
Give me the catheter. Get a crash cart.
他心跳骤停了
He's in cardiac arrest.
或许你下次实践会好一点儿
Maybe your second time will go better.
终于有机会看到真人大小的陶博
So we finally know what Taub would look like
是个什么样子了
if he were life-size.
可以回办公室了吗
Can we go back to the office now?
开什么玩笑
You kidding?
我们还要做鉴别诊断呢
We got a differential to run.
心律失调
Cardiac arrhythmia.
我昨晚凭这海报春宵一度
That poster got me laid when I got home last night,
爱怎么画随你
so do your worst.
心律失调证明了我的观点
Arrhythmia proves I was right.
杰克的病灶在心脏  不在脑部
Jack's problem is his heart, not his brain.
你没上广告的时候  在外面睡小护士
So when you're not on a billboard, you sleep with nurses.
上了广告之后  回家跟老婆睡
But when you are, you sleep with your wife.
我觉得你把顺序弄反了
I think you got that backwards.
旁边那胳膊肘是我的
That's my elbow in the corner.
你老婆今天有空吗
What's your wife doing later?
居然剪掉奇斯留了你
Huh. They chose you and cut out Chase?
显然市场部认为
Apparently, marketing thinks my face
我这张脸最值得信赖
is the most trustworthy.
真的假的
For real?
病人两次心脏骤停
Both of our patients' cardiac incidents
都出现在身体应激之后
happened after physical stress.
我猜可能是血管迷走神经晕厥
I'm guessing vasovagal syncope?
无聊
Buzzkill.
血管迷走神经晕厥该在病人年轻时有所显现
Vasovagal syncope would manifest at a much younger age.
-有可能是药物引起  -毒检结果正常
- Could be drugs. - Tox screen was clean.
会不会是植物神经功能紊乱
What about autonomic nervous system dysfunction?
可能引起心律失调和昏迷
It could cause arrhythmia and fainting.
冒犯你了吗
Inappropriate?
我是指  你们犹太人会不会很介意
I mean, 'cause of the Jew thing?
自主神经功能紊乱
Autonomic nervous system dysfunction...
我喜欢
I like it.
做脑垂体活检
Let's biopsy his pituitary gland.
肾上腺静脉抽样才更合道理
Adrenal venous sampling makes more sense
而且侵袭性更小
and is a less invasive procedure...
可你毫不在意
Which you don't care about,
因为你就是想检查脑垂体
because you just want to check the pituitary,
因为你还是认为
because you still think
他的脑子有问题
there's something wrong with the guy's brain?
瞒不过你呀
Can't fool you.
他没有其它脑垂体病变的症状
He has no other symptoms for pituitary disease.
我们不能因为你不相信英雄主义
We can't stick a needle in his brain
就用探针刺人家脑子
because you don't believe in heroism.
好  按你们说的做
Fine, do it your way.
白白浪费半天时间
You'll waste half a day,
反正我看他也不急着恢复康复
but I'm sure he's in no hurry to get better.
自主神经系统
The autonomic nervous system
控制人体的非自主行为  比如心跳
controls involuntary actions, like your heartbeat.
如果推测正确  病症可以控制
If we're right, it's manageable,
但仍会恶化
but will progress.
我们可以请他来会诊一下吗
Do you think we can consult with him?
原来你认识陶博医生
I didn't know you knew Dr. Taub.
我不认识他
I don't.
你看见广告了
You saw the ADs.
我没别的意思  只是你昨天的诊断不对
Look, no offense, but you were wrong yesterday.
而且如果他医术不高明的话
And they wouldn't have made him the face of the hospital
医院也不会用他做形象代言是吧
if he weren't really good, right?
陶博医生
Dr. Taub...
病人请你过来
The patient would like to see you.
有什么能效劳的吗
How can I help?
我失算了  你们俩会私底交流
I forgot. You guys talk.
好吧  对你们两个没有冒犯之心
Look, no offense to either of you,
可是要我陪你妈妈吃晚饭
but dinner with your mom?
开玩笑嘛  我还得装得人模人样的
Come on, I-I'd have to act like a decent human being,
你也知道我装相的时候多紧张
and you know what a strain that puts on me.
你呢  自从跟萨姆分手以后
And, you, ever since you broke up with Sam,
整天除了闷闷不乐就是唉声叹气
you've done nothing but mope and whine.
真是烦得我要死要活
It's an unbelievable bummer.
我就想知道到底什么事那么有趣
And just what is so exciting
值得你把我们两个都推掉
you have to blow off both of us to do it?
我只是想穿着短裤坐在自家沙发上
I just want to sit on my couch in my underwear,
喝威士忌
drink scotch,
一个人静静地  看《新泽西娇妻》
and watch The Real Housewives of New Jersey... by myself.
我只想闲一个晚上
I just want one night off.
这要求很过分吗
Is that so much to ask?
-过分  -过分
- Yes. - Yes.
我们两你必须选一个
You have to choose one of us.
我选威尔森
I choose Wilson.
很好
Good...
他也来给我过生日
Because he's coming to my birthday dinner.
我才没唉声叹气
I do not whine.
杰克不是爱逞英雄的人
Jack's not exactly the hero type.
上大学的时候他组建了这个乐队
He started this band in college.
他们全国巡演  寻找机遇
They gig around the country, looking for their big break.
已经16年了
It's been 16 years.
你和戴茜一定很苦
That must be hard on you and Daisy.
我觉得自己像个单身母亲
It's like I'm a single parent.
我那么爱他
I love him so much.
但我已经心力憔悴了
But I'm at the end of my rope.
杰克昨天的作为令人佩服
What Jack did yesterday was so incredible,
以至于我们老板认为
our boss assumed his illness
他可能是疾病的影响才有此举
had something to do with his behavior.
但如果事实并非如此
But if that's not the case,
那对他而言就比你想象中意义更大
there's more to him than you think.
你觉得陶博能算院里
You think Taub really comes across
最值得信赖的医生吗
as the most trustworthy doctor here?
我知道你为什么烦心
I knew it was bugging you.
-他们居然不用我  -你长太好了
- They cut me out. - You're a pretty boy.
有女人缘  没病人缘
Works well with the ladies, not so much with the patients.
没人想找内衣模特
No one wants an underwear model
给自己做脾切除术
performing their splenectomy.
我看他们踏破铁鞋
Well, I notice they weren't exactly knocking down your door
也没找你当可靠医生
looking for Dr. Trustworthy.
那是因为我是黑人
That's 'cause I'm black.
皮质醇[肾上腺素]水平正常  我们错了
Cortisol levels look normal. We were wrong.
用豪斯的话说  他对了
Which House will interpret as him being right.
他会强迫我们做脑垂体的活检
He's gonna make us biopsy the pituitary gland.
作为一个被种族歧视者包围的人
You seem pretty calm for a guy
你看起来挺淡定的
who's surrounded by racists.
在普林斯顿80%都是白人
80% of the Princeton population is white.
有些是种族主义者  有些不是
Some are racist. Some aren't.
白人两种都有
White works with both demographics.
所以你觉得
So race is your excuse,
没选你是因为种族歧视
not the fact that you usually look
而不是你脸上老一副要揍人一拳的表情
like you're about to punch someone in the face?
一切正常
We're good.
血氧饱和度在下降
O2 sats are dropping.
他停止呼吸了  抽吸
He's not breathing. Suction.
血氧饱和度在回升
Sats are coming back.
是痰栓
Mucus plug.
有点怪
That's weird.
肺部有积液
Fluid in the lungs.
肺炎吗
Pneumonitis?
这和谁的推测都不符合
That doesn't fit with anyone's theory.
测试终于排除了大脑的问题
Our tests finally rule out the brain.
那就剩下心脏和肺部
That leaves the heart and the lungs.
肺炎可能是由细菌
Pneumonitis can be caused by bacteria,
寄生虫  或某种阻塞引起
parasite, some kind of an obstruction.
铁轨上的女孩是谁
Who was the girl on the tracks?
新闻报道上说她叫克洛伊·杰弗里斯
News story said her name was Chloe Jeffries.
问这个干嘛
Why does that matter?
如果不是他有病
'Cause there's another reason besides being sick
那他为个陌生人冒生命危险就另有原因
that he'd risk his life for a stranger.
她不是个陌生人
She's not a stranger.
这位可怜的少女是癫痫病患者
The damsel in distress is an epileptic.
所以我们以为她是癫痫发作
So we assumed she was having an epileptic seizure,
如果不是呢
but what if she wasn't?
-如果她也病了呢  -杰克常巡演在外
- What if she's sick too? - Jack is away a lot on tour.
但他估计不会向我们透露半点实情
What happens on the road stays on the road.
最有可能是感染引起的肺炎
The most likely cause of pneumonitis is infection.
我们不该做个痰栓培养吗
Shouldn't we be getting a sputum culture?
白细胞数
There's no significant elevation
没有明显升高
of white blood cell count.
这更像是中毒
This is more like toxic exposure.
他说得有道理
He's got a point.
凭什么你假设他愧疚
Why is your assumption of his guilt more valid
比我假设他无私更合理
than my assumption of his selflessness?
因为我的假设
Because my assumption is backed up
由无数男人验证  还有陶博
by millions of men, and Taub,
因为他们对自己的妻子不忠
who've cheated on their wives.
去找那个姑娘  搜搜他们的爱巢吧
Find the girl and the love nest.
每个超人都有自己的氪星啊
Every hero has his Kryptonite.
有人吗
Hello?
我们在这儿私闯民宅
So we're breaking into this girl's apartment
就因为豪斯认为
because House thinks that two people,
两个在地铁站里相距30英尺的人
standing 30 feet apart on a subway platform
一定是情人
have to be lovers.
你今天可有够无聊的
God, you're a drag today.
让我猜猜  又和老婆吵架了
Let me guess. Back to fighting with the wife?
没  我们昨晚做爱来着
No. We had sex again last night...
两次
Twice...
今早还一次
And again this morning.
瑞切尔已经很久没和我
Rachel hasn't wanted this much intimacy
这么亲密了
in a long time.
我觉得她迷恋的不是我
I don't think it's me she's hot for.
而是网上那个家伙
It's this Internet guy.
她开心了
She's just happy,
让她充满激情
and that's turning her on.
她没有对你不忠
So she's not cheating on you,
你还性福满满
and you're getting all the action you can handle.
这有什么不好吗
I don't see the downside.
杰克的乐队叫什么
What was Jack's band called?
自杀  什么
Suicide...Something.
自杀季节
Suicide Season.
他们确实认识
She does know him.
问题是  他们是怎么病的
Question is, how'd they get sick?
氪星
Kryptonite.
心电图没有异常
EKG's unremarkable,
甲状腺  肝脏和肾脏功能良好
thyroid, liver, and kidney function seems fine.
你非常健康
You're perfectly healthy.
我希望你再看看仔细
I wish that you would take a second look.
我一直感到疲倦
I'm tired all the time,
天冷的时候
and when it's cold,
我肩膀疼得很奇怪
I get this weird pain in my shoulder.
我还腿疼呢
I have a pain in my leg.
我可没抱怨过
You don't hear me complaining...
刚才那句不算
Except for just now.
医生们都是怎么想的
How do doctors get this idea
怎么会认为你是最好的
you're better than everyone else?
可能就是一些
Probably all that pulling people back
把人从鬼门关拉回来的小意思
from the brink of death.
我瞎猜的
It's just a guess.
我女儿也是医生
My own daughter is a doctor.
她习惯性地无视我的担忧
She makes a hobby of dismissing my concerns.
听起来她很聪明
She sounds smart.
她让你这么说的吗
Did she tell you to say that?
我又没见过你女儿
I've never met your daughter.
真叫人难以相信
That's hard to believe
你现在跟她的"关系"可密切呢
since you are currently shtupping her.
大事不妙
We have a situation.
-蟑螂军团  哪里找到的  -克洛伊的公寓
- Roach bombs, where? - In Chloe's apartment.
谁是克洛伊
Who's Chloe?
听着
Uh, look,
我们不关心你的私人生活
we don't care about your personal life.
我们不会告诉你妻子的
We're not gonna tell your wife.
我真的一点也不明白你们在说什么
I honestly have no idea what you're talking about.
看看谁来看杰克啦
Guess who showed up looking for Jack.
嗨
Hey.
Hi.
你还好吧
You okay?
报纸上说你去了另一家医院
The E.M.T. Said you'd gone to another hospital.
他们留我隔夜观察了  我没事
They held me overnight for observation. I'm fine.
我必须来这里
I had to come here to...
我不知道你为什么要救我
I don't know why you did it,
但是谢谢你
but thank you.
不客气
You're welcome.
我该带点花来的
I should have brought flowers or something.
你就像我的守护神一样
You're like my guardian angel.
不  我只是个乐队小子
No. I'm just a guy in a band.
你听说过他们吗
Maybe you've heard of them?
自杀季节
Suicide Season?
我的一位护士给过我Cd
One of my nurses gave me the CD.
我还没来得及听
I haven't had a chance to listen to it yet,
但是我有种预感
but I have a feeling
我会成为你最狂热的粉丝
I'm going to be your biggest fan.
请你咳嗽一下
I'm gonna need you to cough.
你干嘛呢
What are you doing?
采集痰液培养
Getting a sputum culture.
很显然他们不认识对方
They obviously don't know each other,
所以不是中毒
so it's not toxic exposure.
就只剩下我的推测了  感染
Just leaves my theory-- infection.
请你咳一口痰
If you could just cough up a sample,
我们就能测试病原体了
we can, uh, test for pathogens.
对不起
Sorry, um... Sorry, nothing--
我喉咙里没有痰
there's nothing coming up.
或许我可以帮帮你
Well, maybe I can help you.
疼死我了
Ohh! It hurts!
怎么了
What's the matter?
瞳孔等大等圆  对光敏感
Round, equal, reactive to light.
不是中风
It's not a stroke.
不是我的头
No, it's not my head.
是我的耳朵
It's my ears.
"当我看到她躺在那里  我就想
"When I saw her lying there, I thought,
'我不能傻站在这里眼睁睁看她死去
"'I can't just stand here and let her die.
她应该度过她美好的一生'"
She has her whole life to live.'"
他跳下去不是因为病了
He didn't jump because he was sick
或者认识那女孩
or because he knew that girl.
即使你也得承认这点
Even you have to admit that now.
即使如此  他也不是英雄
Yes, but that doesn't make him a hero.
不过是个傻瓜
It makes him an idiot.
新闻头条不是"傻瓜被地铁撞死"
The only reason that headline doesn't say
的唯一原因就是他运气好
"Moron crushed by train" is luck.
那下条新闻就该是
Next headline is gonna be
"傻瓜没被确诊
"Moron goes undiagnosed
因为医生们不愿讨论他耳朵疼的问题"
because doctors won't talk about his ear pain."
耳朵疼痛符合我的推论
Ear pain fits with my theory.
杰克的感染扩散到了乳突处
Jack has an infection that's spread to his mastoid.
很好  一周后  你的神秘组织
Great. We'll confirm that in a week,
培养完成时就能确诊了
when your secret cultures have sprouted.
我惹麻烦了吗
Am I in trouble?
只有在你浪费我的时间时我才会生气
I only get mad when you waste my time.
你自己的时间我就不管了
Couldn't care less about yours.
不过发现结果是阴性时记得告诉我
But let me know when they come back negative,
我好嘲笑你
and I'll mock you.
你还有更好的主意吗
You have a better idea?
没  所以我要点个芝麻
Nope, so I'm gonna pick one at random.
听神经瘤
Acoustic neuroma.
耳朵里有个肿瘤  说得通
A tumor in the ear-- makes sense.
如果它压迫了
And if it's putting pressure
脑中的呼吸中枢  就解释了肺的问题
on the breathing centers in his brain, explains the lungs.
肺又能解释心脏问题
The lungs explain the heart.
做听觉诱发电位检查
Evoked auditory potential test.
这时间算我的
This counts as my time.
你们能搞定吧
You guys got this?
我这几个月都尽可能
I have been going out of my way
友善的对待犹太老太太
to be nice to old Jewish ladies for months now
就怕其中之一是你妈
on the off chance one of them could be your mom.
你就不能告诉我她不再是犹太人了吗
You couldn't have mentioned she's a shiksa?
嫁给我爸以后就不是了
She converted when she mared my dad.
为时已晚了
You see, now is too late.
我有没怪你
I'm not blaming you for this.
她就想出其不意
She's the one who ambushed you
来了解你的为人
to find out what you were like,
因为我"什么事都不告诉她"
because I "Never tell her anything."
对此我深表同意
I'd have to agree with her on that one.
总之  明显我现在没法赴约了
Anyway, I obviously can't come to dinner now.
很明显
Obviously?
她不仅疯狂还讨厌我
Well, she's crazy, and she hates me.
豪斯...
House...
我要你来吃晚饭  就两小时
I need you to come to that dinner for two hours,
管好你的嘴  像个成年人那样
keep your mouth shut, and behave like an adult.
没错  你不会好过
Yes, you will be in hell,
不过有你在  我会好受些
but I will feel better having you there.
这才是情侣
That is what a relationship is.
有难同当
We average our misery.
这真是...
That was...
出人意料
Unexpected.
我今天心情很好
I'm having a good day.
终于解决了和我妹妹的问题
I finally resolved that thing with my sister.
怎么了
What thing?
我们为是否该送爸爸
Oh, we had the worst fight
去疗养院的事大吵了一架
over whether it's time to put dad in that facility.
已经好几个礼拜了
Been sick over it for weeks.
你从来没提过你妹妹的事
You never mentioned anything about your sister.
实际上我跟菲尔聊了很多
I actually talked a lot about it with Phil.
我该回去工作了
I should be getting back.
现在好了
It's fine now.
不是什么大事
I-it's no big deal.
你爱上他了吗
Are you in love with him?
我从没见过他
I've never met him.
I波和III波在70分贝时正常
Waves one and three normal at 70 decibels.
已经37分钟了
It's been 37 minutes,
一切正常
and everything is normal.
豪斯又错了  没有肿瘤
House is wrong again. He doesn't have a tumor.
豪斯一般不接受
House doesn't usually accept
"我们中途放弃了"这种答案
"We gave up halfway" as an answer.
如果能弄到距感染源更近的体液
If I could get fluid closer to the sources of infection,
我就能做更好的培养
I could get better cultures,
以证实我的理论
prove my theory.
我去准备耳部引流和胸腔穿刺
I'm gonna set up for an ear drainage and thoracentesis.
最多是浪费我自己的时间
I'll only be wasting my time.
她还是个学生
She's a student.
得有人从旁指导
Somebody's got to go with her.
我救了那个女孩  我成功了
I saved that girl. I did that.
我真为你骄傲
And I'm really proud of you.
整件事情让我不禁去想
This whole thing has made me wonder...
如果我死了怎么办
If things could be different.
我经常不在你们身边
I have spent so much time away from you.
是啊  那是因为你热爱你的音乐
Yeah, well, you love your music.
不只是这样
But it's not just that.
我觉得我一直...
I think that I have been...
在害怕...
afraid...
怕我会把事情搞砸
that I would screw things up,
怕我不能成为
that I couldn't be the man
你和戴茜需要的那个依靠
you and Daisy needed me to be.
不过看来我能做得更好
But maybe I'm better than that.
不是吗
Hmm?
我要退出乐队
I am going to quit the band.
我们会喜欢的
I think we'd like that.
耳朵还疼吗
Hey, how's the ear pain?
吃了药好多了
It's better with the drugs,
不过还是很疼
but it still really hurts.
我们要从你的耳朵和肺里
We are going to take some fluid samples
采集一些体液样本
from your ear and your lung.
你能起来吗  向前趴
Can you get up? Lean forward.
趴这上面
Lean on this.
好了  这是利多卡因
Okay, this is Lidocaine.
能起到麻醉作用
It'll numb you up.
好的
Okay.
太奇怪了
This is weird.
怎  怎么了
What--what's the matter?
我耳朵不疼了
The pain in my ear is gone.
不疼了  完全不疼了吗
Gone? Completely?
没错  就在你扎完针以后
Yeah, when you stuck me in the back.
这意味着什么
What does that mean?
乖  这是弄给你吃的
Okay, I'm just cutting that for you.
好吃好吃
Yum yum.
她...她还吃别的吗
Is...is she going to eat anything else
还是只吃奶酪和饼干
or just the cheese and crackers?
她正处于挑食阶段  反正也不会怎样
She's going through a picky phase--it won't kill her.
你才是她妈
You're her mother.
就我所知
All I know is,
你和你妹妹这么大时
when you and your sister were growing up,
我们吃什么你们就吃什么
you ate what we ate.
从不挑食
No excuses.
能把盐递给我吗
Would you pass the salt?
她今早吃了鸡蛋和很多水果
She had eggs this morning and lots of fruit.
原来如此
Ah. That explains it.
什么
Explains what?
今天下午在公园的时候
She was a little Vilder Chaiah
她简直没法管
in the park this afternoon.
我说什么她都不听
She wouldn't listen to anything I said.
非要用糖哄才行
Must have been all the sugar.
实际上  这个
Actually, the whole
糖果能让孩子听话绝对是扯谎
sugar-makes-kids-hyperactive thing is a myth.
有人做过研究
It's a study.
我想那一定很有趣
I'm sure it's very interesting.
我从来不看那些  我只抚养孩子长大
I didn't read any studies. I just raised children.
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
你怎么可能知道
How are you supposed to keep up
她一整天都吃了什么  你总是不在家
with what she eats all day? You're never home.
不好意思
I'm sorry.
我得接个电话
I have to get this.
告诉我你们需要我
Tell me you need me.
杰克没得癌症
Jack doesn't have cancer.
太棒了  我马上就来
God, that's awful. I'll be right in.
马斯特斯在他背上打了针利多卡因
Masters stuck him in the back with Lidocaine,
他耳朵就不疼了
and his ear pain went away.
你不用来
We don't need you here.
我们只是想搞明白
We just need to figure out
这家伙的身体怎么会认为他耳朵长在背上
why this guy's body thinks his ear is on his back.
因为他的耳朵本来是别的部位
Because his ear used to be something else.
当你还是胎儿时  细胞聚集在一起
When you're a fetus, your cells are close together.
胚胎发育时
When you grow,
它们开始生长并分化
they spread out and specialize.
有的时候会出差错  一部分细胞
Sometimes the body screws up,
仍然停留在胚胎时期的位置
and they keep the old area codes,
共用同一个痛感中枢
report to the same pain centers.
牵涉性疼痛
Referred pain.
不光长得俊  还挺聪明啊
Looks and brains.
针刺他背部时  连接脊髓疼痛中枢
When you stuck him in the back, you cut off communication
的传导通路被截断了
with the pain centers in his spinal cord.
我们需要弄清楚
So we just need to figure out
疼痛信号到底是从哪里发出来的
where the message is actually coming from.
会不会是甲状腺
What about his thyroid?
甲状腺功能亢进可以解释他的所有症状
Hyperthyroidism would explain all his symptoms.
也有可能是肝脏的原因
Or it could be his liver.
那我们就都查一查
Good. We'll take a look at both.
声明一下  牵涉性疼痛并不能排除感染
For the record, referred pain does not rule out infection--
你在攻读数学学位的时候
Were you like this when you were working
就已经这样了吗
for your math degree?
假如欧几里德来做客座讲座
If Euclid had been a guest lecturer,
你会不会直接坐到第一排大声说
would you have been the kid sitting in the front row going,
不好意思  你还没证明勾股定理呢
"Actually, you haven't proven the pythagorean theorem"?
喂
Hello?
好了
All right.
妈妈
Mom...
谢谢你  亲爱的
Thank you, sweetie.
假设你们两个结婚了
So say you two got married,
你会皈依犹太教吗
would you convert to Judaism?
我们还没发展到这程度呢  妈妈
We haven't gotten that far, mom.
这确实是个十分有意思的问题
That's actually a really interesting question.
我是个无神论者
I'm an atheist.
亲爱的  我认识的犹太人中有一半不信神
Honey, half the Jews I know are atheists.
主要是种归属感
It's about community.
豪斯对归属感没什么兴趣
House isn't that big on community.
你为什么老叫他豪斯
And why do you call him "House"?
他的名字叫格雷戈
The man's name is Greg.
直呼其名会显得你们两个很亲密
It makes it seem like you're not serious.
我只是提醒你该为将来考虑了
I'm just trying to help you think about the future.
你已经...你已经老大不小了
You're-- you're a certain age now.
你找到的男朋友的质量只能越来越差
The parade of boyfriends can't be as amusing as it was.
是该安定下来的时候了  像你妹妹那样
You need to settle down, like your sister.
安定下来  说来好听  其实就是浮云
Settling down isn't all it's cracked up to be.
下周萨姆过生日
Next week is Sam's birthday.
我本想带她去波科诺山
I was gonna take her to the Poconos and--
有点伤感
That's very sad.
这个话题也许并不适合这种喜庆的场合
Perhaps not the best choice of topic for a festive occasion.
我不想让瑞秋
I just don't want Rachel
长大以后以为你是个荡妇
growing up thinking you're a slut.
好吧  该我说点什么了
Okay, I got this.
首先  岳母大人
First of all, mom...
哦  天呐
Oh, my God.
你难道...
Did you...
给我妈用了镇静剂
Sedate my mother?
药力发挥的时机恰到好处
Kicked in just in time.
她过一两个小时之后就能醒
She'll wake up in a couple of hours,
好像什么都没发生过
be good as new.
就当是我送给你的生日礼物
Think of it as my birthday gift to you.
你不让我说话
You told me to keep my mouth shut.
这就是我唯一的办法了
It's the only way I had a chance.
且不说豪斯有社交障碍
Leaving aside the fact that House is a sociopath,
我必须承认...  我确实有种解放的感觉
I have to admit that I'm-- I'm honestly relieved.
你妈妈确实...  确实不好对付
Your mom is quite a h-- quite a handful.
什么
What?
我感觉...
I feel f--
你不是在耍我吧
Oh, you've got to be kidding me.
你也给我下药了
You drugged me too?
对不起
Sorry.
原以为你会胡说八道些什么的
I honestly thought you'd be worse.
就算是送给我自己的礼物
That was my gift to myself.
看起来杰克的甲状腺功能还算正常
I take it Jack's thyroid levels are normal.
福曼正在做肝脏活检
Foreman is doing a liver biopsy now.
很好
Good.
你怎么了
What's up with you?
没什么
Nothing.
我感觉很好
I'm peachy.
感觉自己被别人取代了是不好受
It's hard when you feel like you've been replaced.
我们家有次新买了只小狗崽
We got a new puppy once,
原来的那条可卡长毛狗
and our old cocker spaniel
抑郁了好几个礼拜
just moped for weeks.
你有过性经历吗
Have you even had sex?
我们不是在讨论我的问题
We're not talking about me.
讨论的是你的问题
We're talking about you.
对  你刚才在讲小狗崽的事
No, you're talking about puppies,
我走神了
and I'm not listening.
她总是不停地想做
She wants to do it all the time,
却并不是因为我
but it has nothing to do with me.
我成了她发泄的工具
I'm just a piece of meat.
她喜欢上了别人
Well, she likes someone else,
你也跟别人上过床
and you've slept with other people.
你们为什么还没离婚
Uh, why are you still together?
我爱她
I love her.
我们在一起生活了22年
We've been together for 22 years.
我从没爱上过除她以外的任何人
I've never loved anybody else.
我不知道...
I don't know how to...
离开她要怎么办
Not be with her.
那你以后会对她忠贞不贰吗
So you're never gonna cheat again.
我不知道
I don't know.
那就有点自私了吧
Well, that seems kind of selfish, doesn't it?
福曼发现他肝脏里有弥散性炎症
Foreman found diffuse inflammation in Jack's liver.
看起来像自身免疫肝炎
Looks like autoimmune hepatitis...
要马上给他用激素
Starting him on steroids.
这样多好
Isn't this nice?
这是什么音
What's this note?
听起来像不像A
Does that sound like an "A"?
记住了  手指这样按
Remember, I put my finger like this
把那个东西抬起来  就是F了
without this doohickey on it, it's an "F."
明白了吗
See?
我们能不能看书啊
Can we read a book instead?
当然可以
Yes, we--
杰克
Jack?
杰克  快来人啊
Jack! Help him!
快  快
Come on. Come on.
没事  没事
Okay. Okay.
他昨晚三次癫痫
He seized three times last night.
我们想方设法稳定住了病情
We got him stabilized, but barely.
就算最开始的时候他的大脑没有问题
If there was nothing wrong with his brain before,
现在看来问题不小
there sure is now.
你让我们站在这里盯着病人
Any particular reason we need to be
有什么特别的原因吗
looking at the patient?
有
Yes.
卡迪她妈在我办公室里
Cuddy's mom is in my office,
看起来她是在气头上
and she looks mad.
你犯什么错了
What did you do?
我们这位病人
Our patient also
昨晚还高烧了
developed a raging fever overnight.
这说明马斯特斯早先的判断是对的
That means Masters was right all along.
确实是感染
This is an infection.
用不用给你一分钟时间幸灾乐祸下
Should we give you a minute to gloat?
我们还不知道是什么类型的感染
We still don't know what kind of infection--
可能是细菌  病毒  真菌
could be bacterial, viral, fungal.
等到培养结果...
Until the cultures--
这是我见过最差劲的显摆
You are the worst gloater ever.
她取得样本后就开始做培养了
Her starting those cultures when she did
也就是说还有24小时就能知道结果
means we're 24 hours closer to the answer.
"我们对你丈夫的死感到十分抱歉
"We're sorry your husband croaked,
但至少24小时后我们就能知道结果了"
but at least we were 24 hours closer to the answer."
我们还是继续缩小范围吧
Let's narrow it down, shall we?
四天之前  这家伙趴在了地铁轨道里
Four days ago, the guy was facedown in the subway.
天知道那地方的污泥里面有什么东西
God only knows what's in that sludge.
毒烟能把他熏倒
Toxic fumes make him pass out.
剩下的可能就是老鼠尿的功劳了
Rat pee does the rest.
如果真是钩端螺旋体病
If it's leptospirosis,
这就是历史上病程进展最快的一例了
it's the fastest-moving case in history.
钩端螺旋体病可以发展成脑膜炎
Leptospirosis can turn into meningitis.
你们的意见没法得到验证
I can't confirm any of this yet,
我们已经没有犯错误的时间了
and we don't have time to choose wrong.
符合他的症状
It fits,
既然这是我们想到的唯一的诊断
and since it's the only idea on the table,
我觉得应该按照它来治疗
I say it's a winner.
给他开始用去氧土霉素
Start him on doxycycline.
等等  还是我去吧
No, wait. I'll do it.
你们回办公室去
You guys have to go back to the office,
等布比走了来找我
tell me when Bubbie's gone.
你是医生吗
You a doctor?
当然
Sure.
给你换了新药
You're on new meds.
接着睡吧
Go back to sleep.
我会死吗
Am I gonna die?
但愿不会
Well, I hope not,
你死了我就得回办公室去了
'cause then I'd have to go back to my office.
当然了  如果你把输液管拔了
Of course, if you do kick it,
那你还能再
then you get to be famous
红个两三周吧
for another two, maybe three weeks.
他们说我是英雄吗
They're saying I'm a hero?
没错  但是  你知道的  接下来就轮到
Yeah, but, you know, in a few days,
"熊猫要生三胞胎了"
a panda bear will give birth to triplets,
我们的日子也照样过
and we'll all move on.
抱歉  你特别相信自己是个英雄
Oh, I'm sorry. You actually believe that you are a hero.
你该去笼中斗虎
Should get yourself some tights and a cape,
围着哥谭镇转悠
run around Gotham
从着火的大楼里救孩子
pulling babies out of burning buildings.
或许你依旧很走运
Maybe you'll keep getting lucky.
但你还是以前那个你
You're still the same guy you were last week.
你打算在那坐多久
How long are you gonna sit there?
几个小时吧
Could be hours.
藏在病人身后
Hiding behind a sick guy...
你真够英勇的
That's heroic.
我能解释
I can explain.
有时我会弄混药物
Sometimes I mix up my medications.
我不需要你解释什么
I don't need you to explain anything.
我想你我心知肚明
I think we both know that...
我欠你一个道歉
I owe you an apology.
你说什么
Say what?
我甚至想不起来昨晚我是怎么爬上床的
I don't even remember going to bed last night.
我一定是喝多了
I must have had too much to drink.
我知道自己有时比较难相处
I do know I can be difficult.
你是有一点八婆
You were a little bitchy.
在诊疗室里  你表现得就像个蠢蛋
In the clinic, you were a complete schmendrick,
但当你知道我是丽莎的母亲后
but once you knew I was Lisa's mother,
你说话就注意多了
you held your tongue.
因为你爱她
That's because you love her.
不过我还是认为
I still think you're a pain in the ass
你缺乏上帝情节
with a God complex,
你要是敢伤害她  就是找死
and I'll kill you if you hurt her,
但我很高兴她有你在身旁
but I'm glad she has you.
现在我们不是还得拥抱吧
We don't have to hug now, do we?
你在瞎想什么
What do you think?
我要去赶火车了
I've got a train to catch.
我以为你到周日才走
I thought you were staying till Sunday.
我可是冒着感冒来的
I'm coming down with a cold.
每次我和丽莎或者她妹妹在一起的时候
Every time I stay with Lisa or her sister,
那些小孩都会让我生病
one of those rug rats gets me sick.
小孩最麻烦了
Children are awful.
她最近出过疹子吗
Did she have a rash recently?
没出过  怎么了
No. What's going on?
发烧呢  发痒呢
Feverish, itchy?
都没有过
No.
她在这里做什么
What is she doing here anyway?
现在还是上午  她不该在学校里吗
It's the middle of the morning. Shouldn't she be in school?
我给她请了几天假
I'm keeping her out for a few days.
-学校里正在闹...  -水痘
- There's been a little outbreak... -Chicken pox.
抱歉  但要是我让你说完刚才的话
Sorry, but if I let you finish that sentence,
那就没这么令人印象深刻了
that would be much less impressive.
对孩子来说水痘不是什么大病
Chicken pox is no big deal for kids,
但对成年人来说
but it's a terrible, horrible,
它是很糟糕  很可怕  很不好  很要命的事
no-good, very bad deal for grown-ups.
你认为杰克得了水痘
You think Jack has chicken pox?
但他没有起水疱
But he doesn't have blisters.
他也不痒  而且戴茜也没出水痘
He's not itchy, and Daisy never got it.
我知道
I know.
再说一遍  当我察觉到的时候
Again, that's why it's so impressive
这就是为什么令人印象深刻
that I figured it out.
百分之五的病人不会出水疱
5% of cases present without blisters.
而孩子只是个病菌携带者
The kid was just a carrier.
我会给你用抗水痘球蛋白
I'm gonna start you on anti-varicella gamma globulin,
这会救你的命
which will save your life.
但开药不会让我变成英雄
But it won't make me a hero.
你感觉怎么样
How are you feeling?
感觉我还活着
Like I'm not gonna die.
我简直等不及想接你回家了
I can't wait to take you home.
乐队的那些家伙们打来电话
The guys called.
媒体帮我们办了几场演唱会
All this press has got us a couple of new gigs--
就几天  最多三周
just a few more dates, three weeks, tops.
离开三周也没那么糟
Three weeks isn't so bad.
这不是三周的事
It's not three weeks.
而是他的所作所为  不停地追加演出
It's what he's always done-- just one more tour.
我很遗憾
I'm sorry.
是呀  最可悲的地方在于
Yeah, the pathetic thing is
我说服自己相信他能改变
I let myself believe that he could change,
他可以变成别的样子
he could be this other guy.
没什么比爱上一个
There's nothing worse than loving someone
一再让你失望的人更糟糕的了
who's never going to stop disappointing you.
培养实验证明杰克的确得了水痘
Culture confirmed Jack does have chicken pox.
只是多花了六个小时
It just took six hours longer.
活检的结果也一样
Autopsy works too.
顺便一提  你的英雄其实是个失败者
Fyi, turns out your hero is a loser.
他要接着上路了
He's going back on the road.
他依然冒着生命危险救了那位女士
He still risked his life for that woman.
那是冲动所致  很简单
That was impulse. That was easy.
处理家庭关系才难
Dealing with family is hard.
等一下  还有一件事我也说对了
Wait, that's another thing I got right.
我们现在是几比几了
How many does that make?
你几分啊
And how many for you?
你得瑟的时候我痛击你来着
I'm also kicking your ass at gloating.
我认为我们应该离婚
I think we should get a divorce.
你对他有好感  我忍受不了
You have feelings for him, and I can't handle that.
但这是我的问题
But it's my fault
你需要其他人
you needed someone else.
-我一直在伤害你  -我们彼此相爱
- I keep hurting you. - We love each other.
我知道
I know.
但你过得开心吗
But are you happy?
不开心
No.
那我们在做什么
Then what are we doing?
你知道吗  鉴于你的基因影响
You know, you turned out remarkably close to normal,
你真是难得的正常啊
considering the genes in play.
谢谢
Thanks.
拿着这个...
Here...
以防你妈妈回来
In case your mom comes back.
生日快乐
Happy Birthday.
你是大甜心先生
Oh, you are a sweet, sweet man.
你会来吗
You coming over?
会的
Yes.
不  我去不了
Oh, no, I can't.
因为威尔森
Wilson.
到了保龄球之夜了
It's, uh, bowling night.
要是我不去  他一定不会轻饶我的
He'll never forgive me if I don't.
去他的  我去你那里
Oh, screw it. I'm coming.
不不不  我可不要担这个责任
No, no, no. I am not gonna be responsible for that.
你给他下了药  你得还他个保龄球之夜
You drugged the man. You go bowling with him.
但我跟威尔森
Well, my chances of sex
可不太能做爱啊
are considerably lower with Wilson.
好吧
Fine.
你准备好了吗
Hey. You ready?
是这样的...
Here's the thing...
重申一遍  这个会面是关于我和坚持我的界线
Again, this meeting is about me and setting my bounds.
也和我有关
Well, it's about me too,
迪娜  我也是有界线的
and I have my boundaries, Dina,
而你和你的整个家庭
and they have clearly been crossed
却侵犯了我的界线
by you and your entire family.
这不是真的
That's not true.
迪娜  我们都要做出让步
We all need improvements, Dina,
是你让我这样的
and I formed my opinion on you. Shh.
瞎说  别嘘我  迪娜
No, don't shush me, Dina.
不  我要嘘你是应为你不让我说完话
No, I will shush you because you're not letting me finish.